在最后几个大的任务当中，我想要解决的是
And one of the last big tasks that I wanna tackle is adaptive
这个应用的自适应布局
layout for an application.
回想一下我们要完成的目标：
Recall what we wanted to accomplish was to take
当我们处于条形状态
the details from the right and
要把右边的细节内容转移到列表的下方去
move it under the list whenever we're in a narrow layout.
然后我们足够宽的时候
But when we're in a wide layout,
我们就想要它回到右边原来的位置
then we want it to be where it's at right now.
所有我们添加一个视觉状态管理器
So we'll add a VisualState Manager and
以及一些状态，然后让它工作
some VisualStates, and we'll get it to work.
然后在下一节视频中我们会为应用添上最后的功能
And then we'll do any cleanup on the UI that we need to
在那之前，还要去做一些UI界面上的清理工作
before we add our last feature in the next video.
所有我们现在就从这里开始吧
So let's go ahead and get started here.
我要在这个上一节中添加的这个格子下面
I'm going to, underneath this first grid that I added in
再添加上一个视觉状态管理器
the previous video, I'm going to start with the visual state
以及一堆视觉状态组
manager and add a bunch of visual state groups.
我们创建一个视觉状态组，就叫它VisualStateGroup.
We'll create one visual state group called Visual State Group.
然后我还要创建
And then I'm gonna create.
一个单独的视觉状态，然后拷贝一下
A single visual state,and I'll copy and
粘贴出第二条
paste it to create a second one.
所以，第一条，我们就叫它“wide”
So this first one,we're gonna call Wide.
有了状态触发器之后，它就会生效
And this one will be valid,with the state trigger.
所以创建VisualState.StateTriggers,以及
So VisualState.StateTriggers and let me go ahead and
创建VisualState.Setters，好滴
create VisualState.Setters,great.
这里触发器的设置
And here are the triggers,
窗口的最小宽度是800
the minimum window width will be 800.
我们可以用我们的手机测试，确保看起来美观
We can test this with our phone to make sure it looks good,
用手机模拟器也可以
with the phone emulator that that will work.
如果不的话。。我想在手机上也应该可以的
If not, well, I think it will be fine on the phone.
主要是桌面端，要怎么样才能看起来美观
It's just a matter of the desktop, how it looks.
无论如何，我们会测试的
Any rate, we'll test it.
好滴，到设置器这
All right, setters.
我们开始，Setter Target
，Here we go. Setter Target=,
在这里事情就变得有趣了,对吧
okay, so this is where things start to get interesting, right.
我们实际要做的是，我看看，我们把详情窗口
What we really wanna do is take,let's see, we take this detail
详情窗格里面的一切
grid, everything inside of the detail grid, and
这里面的确包含了很多东西
you know it does contain quite a bit.
基于现在的视觉状态，我们要把它移动到
And we wanna move it to a different column and
另一个不同的行列中去
row based on the current visual state.
我一下不知道该怎么办了，来看一下
I think I've lost my mind here,there we go.
所以我想要合理地设置详情窗格的行和列
So I wanna set the detail grids row and
要做到那样，我需要
column appropriately, and to do that, I'm gonna need to
通过名字来应用它，但是我又在使用依附的属性值
，access it through its name, but I'm using attached properties.
所以到底该怎么做
So how do I do that?
我想我们应该这样
Well, I think we do it like this,
使用DetailGrid.(Grid.Row)
DetailGrid.(Grid.Row) and
把它的值设为0
we set its value equal to 0, and
然后对列做同样的事情
we'll do something similar with a column.
使用列值应该为1
So the column value would be 1.
然后继续，复制一下视觉状态，粘贴一下
And then let's go ahead and copy this visual state, paste it,
我们想要设置窗口的最小宽度值
and we wanna set the minimumwindow width for
这个设为0，这样就变成长条状了
this one to 0, andthis is gonna be narrow.
我们把它颠倒一下
And we're gonna reverse it.
行为1，列为0
The row will be 1 andthe column will be 0,
这是长条下的状态
and the narrow VisualState.
让我们看看我们得到了啥
All right,let's see what we have, and
然后根据目前的状态再做一些其他的调整
then we may need to make some other adjustments based on that.
好，让我们开始，选择一个
Okay, so let's go ahead and select.
我们的数据还有30秒进入战场
Our data, and just go ahead and get all queued up here.
好滴，我们有了一个本子
All right,we have one comic book left.
哦，真棒
Okay, great.
看起来右边我们仍还有一些问题要解决
And it looks like I still have some issues here on the right.
稍后在UI界面整理阶段我们再处理
We'll have to work on that in the UI cleanup phase.
我得到了一个确定的点，小于它，就离开界面了
I'm gonna get to a certain point, where it goes off screen,
你可以在下面看到它了
and you can see it below.
哦，这样看起来糟糕极了
Boy, that does not look good at all.
我想我还需要多做一些调整
So, I think we're gonna need to make one more change and
然后还有一些清理工作
then a little bit of clean up here.
我们要做的调整是
The change that we need to make,and
让我们同样地先选另一个人物
let's just pick another one of these as well.
我选择Carnage
Let's pick Carnage.
一起看看有没有其他有趣的事情，没有
Let's see if we get anything interesting there, no.
好的，这里
All right, there we go.
在这里我们看到了有意思的事情
Okay, gets a little more interesting there.
你注意到这些跑出了界面的边缘
You'll notice that these runoff to the side of the screen.
当我们有了一个描述，或者说一个标题
When we had a description or a title,
它跑到了界面的边缘之外
it ran off to the side of the screen.
我认为这里的原因是
And I think the problem there is the width for
这里的宽度不是这一列的宽度
this entire column right here.
所以让我们这样设置
So, let's set that.
要调整它，首先我给最顶层的窗格一个名字
And to do that, I'm gonna give this topmost grid,
列都在这
the columns here, names.
然后我就可以通过设置“x:name”
And I can do that by using the x:Name= and
先把它叫ColumnOne
we'll just callthis "ColumnOne".
对第二个列做同样的工作
And we'll do the same thing for the second column, like so.
然后在宽状态的时候
So here in the wide state,
我们要做的是
what we wanna do is set
对ColumnOne写上一个设置器
the SetterTarget="ColumnOne.Width".
我们要确保值被设置为Auto
And we'll make sure that's set to Auto.
然后是ColumnTwo 的宽度
And then ColumnTwo.width.
我们把它设置为*
We'll set that to *.
然后在下面做完全相反的事情
And then we'll do the exact opposite.
在长条状态的这里，把*和auto互换一下
When we hit the narrow one,so we'll hit the * there and
希望这样我们能解决问题
Auto there, and hopefully,that'll fix the problem.
来，再跑一遍看看
Okay, let's run it again.
好，选这个Union Jack 看看
Okay, we'll pick Union Jack there.
好的
All right.
问题解决
Great.
真棒
All right,
看起来好像还有一些东西掉到边缘之外去了
looks like I do still have somethings falling off to the side.
我想我们需要包裹一下这个标题
I think I need to wrap the title there.
实话说，我要包裹一些这个标题，然后还要
Honestly, I'll wrap all the titles, and then I need to add
在右手边这里到边界之前添加一些外边距
some more margin on the right hand side here for this.
让我们来实现它
So let's do this.
来到下面漫画详情这里
Let's come down to the comic detail.
我想要
And I want to.
哦不，把它移过去一点
Nope, move that over a little bit.
我要在这里添加一条文字包裹
I want to add in this some text wrapping.
写上TextWrapping="Wrap"
So let's go,TextWrapping="Wrap".
我想我还要到前面去，重复一下这个操作
And I think I'm gonna go ahead and do the same thing,
尽管它还并没有发生过意外
even though we didn't see it happen,
我要为这个DetailNameTextBlock做同样的事
I wanna do the same thing for the DetailNameTextBlock as well.
这样就应该能解决掉问题了
That should handle that problem.
现在我想要做的事是，在右边添加一些外边距
Now I'm also gonna want to add some margin on the right there
两种情况下都需要
in both of these cases.
右边添加上10像素
So I'm gonna put 10 pixels to the right.
这样就能给我们一些喘息的空间
That will give us a little breathing room.
好的，现在我们看看到底发生了什么
All right,let's see what happens now.
选这个Klaw
Let's pick Klaw.
它还在抓取数据，好了
Looks like it's still grabbing,okay, great.
好极了，我喜欢它
All right, I like that.
它的右边不再紧靠了边界了
It doesn't butt right up against it.
真不错，很好，看起来真不错
That's good, that's good,looks great.
让我们选另一个看看
Let's pick another one here.
这也不错
That looks good.
这里你可以看到，它本来想要显示在html当中
You can see that this was intended to be used in HTML.
(笑）让我们看看Bishop
[LAUGH] Let's pick Bishop.
Bishop的照片看起来非常帅
It's a pretty cool picture of Bishop.
我们仍要等待漫画数据传进来
We're still waiting for the comics to roll in.
噢好了
There we go.
一个叫Cable的本子，不错
All right, Cable, good.
朕龙心大悦
Good, good, good.
看起来真不错
That looks awesome.
好，非常刁
Okay, very cool.
好的，这样的话
All right, and so
让我们再来看看实际展开的时候是怎么样的
now let's see what it looks like when we actually scroll out.
好的，看起来也很棒
Okay, still looks good,looks great.
下一件我要做的事是
All right,the next thing I wanna do, and
我非常喜欢它以及他看起来的样子
I'm really enjoying this and enjoying the way it looks,
我要到手机上去测试一下
I'm gonna try it on a phone.
让我们选择手机模拟器，然后启动
So let's put it in the mobile emulator and run it there,
去确保一下一切正常
just to make sure everything looks good.
好的，我们来看看
All right, there we go.
让我们继续，选择一个人物看看
Let's go ahead and select one of these items.
你可以在列表下面看到他了
You can see it's listed below.
天啊，这个描述区域真TM小
Boy, that description area is going to be awfully small.
但是最终的
But ultimately, yeah.
我希望有一种简单的方式把它包裹起来
I wish there was an easy way to wrap around.
我们可能需要好好考虑一下了
Well, we might wanna think about that.
现在我脑子里还没有好的解决方案
I don't really have a good solution in mind just yet.
或者我（笑）我可以把这一整块
Other than [LAUGH] I could put this whole area
放进用户控制里面，这样无论我们
in a user control, and then whenever we're in
处于哪种状态，我们都可以改变它的布局
the narrow width,we could change its layout too.
但我并不想那样去实现
But that's not something I wanna take on.
我甚至不知道它在手机上到底应该怎么显示
I didn't even think about the way this would look on a phone.
如果我要想去发布这一个应用
But that would be the next step that I would have to take if I
这就是我下一步需要解决的问题了
was wanting to release this into the wild.
但是我想现在它已经足够好了
Okay, but I think it's good enough for now.
我还有一个非常想要添加的特性
I have one more cool feature that I wanna add, and
而那就是集成小娜
that is Cortana integration.
噢，想想就鸡冻
So excited about that.
下节课我们就会学到了
We'll learn about it in the next lesson.
那么，到时候见了
We'll see you there, thanks.